Neural Networks are a pretty old
神经网络是一种很古老的算法
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
algorithm that was originally motivated
它最初产生的目的是
by the goal of having machines that can mimic the brain.
制造能模拟大脑的机器
Now in this class, of course
在这门课中
I'm teaching Neural Networks to you
我将向你们介绍神经网络
because they work really well
因为它能很好地解决
for different machine learning problems and
不同的机器学习问题
not, certainly not because they're logically motivated.
而不只因为它们在逻辑上行得通
In this video, I'd like
在这段视频中 我想
to give you some of the background on Neural Networks.
告诉你们一些神经网络的背景知识
So that we can get a sense of what we can expect them to do.
由此我们能知道可以用它们来做什么
Both in the sense of
不管是将其应用到
applying them to modern day
现代的机器学习问题上
machinery problems, as well as for
还是应用到
those of you that might
那些你可能会
be interested in maybe the
感兴趣的问题中 也许
big AI dream of someday
这一伟大的人工智能梦想在未来
building truly intelligent machines.
能制造出真正的智能机器
Also, how Neural Networks might pertain to that.
另外 我们还将讲解神经网络是怎么涉及这些问题的
The origins of Neural Networks was
神经网络产生的原因
as algorithms that try
是人们想尝试设计出
to mimic the brain and
模仿大脑的算法
those a sense that if we
从某种意义上说如果我们
want to build learning systems
想要建立学习系统
while why not mimic perhaps the
那为什么不去模仿
most amazing learning machine we
我们所认识的 最神奇的学习机器——
know about, which is perhaps the
人类的大脑呢
brain. Neural Networks came to
神经网络逐渐兴起于
be very widely used throughout the
二十世纪八九十年代
1980's and 1990's and
应用得非常广泛
for various reasons as popularity
但由于各种原因
diminished in the late
在90年代的后期应用减少了
90's. But more recently,
但是最近
Neural Networks  have had a
神经网络
major recent resurgence.
又东山再起了
One of the reasons for this
其中一个原因是
resurgence is that Neural Networks
神经网络
are computationally some what
是计算量有些
more expensive algorithm and
偏大的算法
so, it was only, you know,
然而
maybe somewhat more recently that
大概由于近些年
computers became fast enough
计算机的运行速度变快
to really run large scale
才足以真正运行起大规模的
Neural Networks and because of
神经网络
that as well as a
正是由于这个原因
few other technical reasons which we'll
和其他一些我们后面会讨论到的
talk about later, modern Neural
技术因素
Networks today are the state
如今的神经网络
of the art technique for many applications.
对于许多应用来说是最先进的技术
So, when you think about mimicking
当你想模拟大脑时
the brain while one of
是指想制造出与人类大脑
the human brain does tell me same things, right?
作用效果相同的机器 对吧？
The brain can learn to
大脑可以学会去
see process images than to
以看而不是听的方式处理图像
hear, learn to process our sense of touch.
学会处理我们的触觉
We can, you know, learn to
我们能学习数学
do math, learn to do
学着做微积分
calculus, and the brain
而且大脑能处理
does so many different and amazing things.
各种不同的令人惊奇的事情
It seems like if you want
似乎如果你想要
to mimic the brain it seems
模仿它
like you have to write lots of different
你得写很多不同的
pieces of software to mimic all
软件来模拟所有
of these different fascinating, amazing things
大脑告诉我们的这些
that the brain tell us, but does
五花八门的奇妙的事情
is this fascinating hypothesis that the
不过能不能假设
way the brain does all of
大脑做所有这些
these different things is not
不同事情的方法
worth like a thousand different programs,
不需要用上千个不同的程序去实现
but instead, the way the
相反的 大脑处理的方法
brain does it is worth
只需要
just a single learning algorithm.
一个单一的学习算法就可以了？
This is just a hypothesis but
尽管这只是一个假设
let me share with you
不过让我和你分享
some of the evidence for this.
一些这方面的证据
This part of the brain, that little
大脑的这一部分
red part of the brain, is
这一小片红色区域
your auditory cortex and
是你的听觉皮层
the way you're understanding my voice
你现在正在理解我的话
now is your ear is
这靠的是耳朵
taking the sound signal and routing
耳朵接收到声音信号
the sound signal to your auditory
并把声音信号传递给你的
cortex and that's what's
听觉皮层 正因如此
allowing you to understand my words.
你才能明白我的话
Neuroscientists have done the
神经系统科学家做了
following fascinating experiments where
下面这个有趣的实验
you cut the wire from
把耳朵到
the ears to the auditory
听觉皮层的神经切断
cortex and you re-wire,
在这种情况下
in this case an animal's brain, so
将其重新接到一个动物的大脑上
that the signal from the eyes
这样从眼睛到
to the optic nerve eventually gets routed to the auditory cortex.
视神经的信号最终将传到听觉皮层
If you do this it turns out,
如果这样做了 那么结果表明
the auditory cortex will learn
听觉皮层将会
to see.
学会“看”
And this is in every single sense
这里“看”代表了
of the word see as we know it.
我们所知道的每层含义
So, if you do this to the animals,
所以 如果你对动物这样做
the animals can perform visual discrimination
那么动物就可以完成视觉辨别任务
task and as they can
它们可以
look at images and make appropriate
看图像 并根据图像
decisions based on the
做出适当的决定
images and they're doing
它们正是通过
it with that piece of brain tissue.
脑组织中的这个部分完成的
Here's another example.
下面再举另一个例子
That red piece of brain tissue is your somatosensory cortex.
这块红色的脑组织是你的躯体感觉皮层
That's how you process your sense of touch.
这是你用来处理触觉的
If you do a similar re-wiring process
如果你做一个和刚才类似的重接实验
then the somatosensory cortex will learn to see.
那么躯体感觉皮层也能学会”看“
Because of this and other
这个实验和其它一些
similar experiments, these are
类似的实验
called neuro-rewiring experiments.
被称为神经重接实验
There's this sense that if
从这个意义上说 如果
the same piece of physical
人体有同一块
brain tissue can process sight
脑组织可以处理光、
or sound or touch then
声或触觉信号
maybe there is one learning
那么也许存在一种学习算法
algorithm that can process
可以同时处理
sight or sound or touch.
视觉、听觉和触觉
And instead of needing to
而不是需要
implement a thousand different programs
运行上千个不同的程序
or a thousand different algorithms to
或者上千个不同的算法来做这些
do, you know, the thousand wonderful things
大脑所完成的
that the brain does, maybe what
成千上万的美好事情
we need to do is figure out
也许我们需要做的就是找出
some approximation or to whatever
一些近似的或
the brain's learning algorithm is and
实际的大脑学习算法
implement that and that the
然后实现它
brain learned by itself how to
大脑通过自学掌握如何
process these different types of data.
处理这些不同类型的数据
To a surprisingly large extent,
在很大的程度上
it seems as if we can
可以猜想如果我们
plug in almost any sensor
把几乎任何一种传感器
to almost any part of
接入到大脑的
the brain and so, within the
几乎任何一个部位的话
reason, the brain will learn to deal with it.
大脑就会学会处理它
Here are a few more examples.
下面再举几个例子
On the upper left is
左上角的这张图是
an example of learning to see with your tongue.
用舌头学会“看”的一个例子
The way it works is--this is
它的原理是 这实际上是
actually a system called BrainPort undergoing
一个名为BrainPort的系统
FDA trials now to help
它现在正在FDA (美国食品和药物管理局) 的临床试验阶段
blind people see--but the
它能帮助失明人士看见事物
way it works is, you strap
它的原理是
a grayscale camera to your
你在前额上带一个灰度摄像头
forehead, facing forward, that takes
面朝前 它就能
the low resolution grayscale image
获取你面前事物的
of what's in front of you
低分辨率的灰度图像
and you then run a wire
你连一根线
to an array of electrodes
到舌头上安装的
that you place on your tongue
电极阵列上
so that each pixel gets mapped
那么每个像素都被映射到
to a location on your
你舌头的
tongue where maybe a
某个位置上
high voltage corresponds to a
可能电压值高的点对应一个
dark pixel and a low voltage
暗像素 电压值低的点
corresponds to a bright
对应于亮像素
pixel and, even as
即使依靠
it does today, with this sort
它现在的功能
of system you and I will
使用这种系统就能让你我
be able to learn to see, you know,
在几十分钟里就学会
in tens of minutes with our tongues.
用我们的舌头“看”东西
Here's a second example of human
这是第二个例子
echo location or human sonar.
关于人体回声定位或者说人体声纳
So there are two ways you can do this.
你有两种方法可以实现
You can either snap your fingers,
你可以弹响指
or click your tongue.
或者咂舌头
I can't do that very well.
这个我做不好
But there are blind people
不过现在有失明人士
today that are actually being
确实在学校里
trained in schools to do this
接受这样的培训
and learn to interpret the pattern
并学会解读
of sounds bouncing off your environment - that's sonar.
从环境反弹回来的声波模式—这就是声纳
So, if after you search
如果你搜索
on YouTube, there are
YouTube之后 就会发现
actually videos of this amazing kid who
有些视频讲述了一个令人称奇的孩子
tragically because of cancer
他因为癌症眼球惨遭移除
had his eyeballs removed, so this is a kid with no eyeballs.
虽然失去了眼球
But by snapping his fingers, he
但是通过打响指
can walk around and never hit anything.
他可以四处走动而不撞到任何东西
He can ride a skateboard.
他能滑滑板
He can shoot a basketball into a
他可以将篮球投入篮框中
hoop and this is a kid with no eyeballs.
注意这是一个没有眼球的孩子
Third example is the
第三个例子是
Haptic Belt where if
触觉皮带
you have a strap
如果你把它
around your waist, ring up
戴在腰上 蜂鸣器会响
buzzers and always have the northmost one buzzing.
而且总是朝向北时发出嗡嗡声
You can give a human a
它可以使人拥有
direction sense similar to
方向感 用类似于
maybe how birds can, you know, sense where north is.
鸟类感知方向的方式
And, some of the bizarre example, but
还有一些离奇的例子
if you plug a third eye
如果你在青蛙身上
into a frog, the frog
插入第三只眼
will learn to use that eye as well.
青蛙也能学会使用那只眼睛
So, it's pretty amazing to
因此 这将会非常令人惊奇
what extent is as if
如果你能
you can plug in almost any sensor
把几乎任何传感器
to the brain and the brain's
接入到大脑中
learning algorithm will just figure
大脑的学习算法就能
out how to learn from that
找出学习数据的方法
data and deal with that data.
并处理这些数据
And there's a sense that
从某种意义上来说
if we can figure out what
如果我们能找出
the brain's learning algorithm is, and,
大脑的学习算法
you know, implement it or implement some approximation
然后在计算机上执行
to that algorithm on a computer, maybe
大脑学习算法或与之相似的算法 也许
that would be our best shot
这将是我们
at, you know, making real progress
向人工智能迈进
towards the AI, the
做出的最好的尝试
artificial intelligence dream of
人工智能的梦想就是
someday building truly intelligent machines.
有一天能制造出真正的智能机器
Now, of course, I'm not
当然我不是
teaching Neural Networks, you know,
教神经网络的
just because they might give us
介绍它只因为它可能为我们
a window into this far-off
打开一扇进入遥远的
AI dream, even though I'm
人工智能梦的窗户
personally, that's one of the things
对于我个人来说
that I personally work on in my research life.
它也是我研究生涯中致力于的一个项目
But the main reason I'm
但我在这节课中
teaching Neural Networks in this
讲授神经网络的原因
class is because it's actually a
主要是对于
very effective state of the
现代机器学习应用
art technique for modern day machine learning applications.
它是最有效的技术方法
So, in the next
因此在接下来的
few videos, we'll start diving into
一些课程中 我们将开始深入到
the technical details of Neural
神经网络的技术细节
Networks so that you
那么你就可以
can apply them to modern-day
将它们应用到现代
machine learning applications and get
机器学习的应用中
them to work well on problems.
并利用它们很好地解决问题
But for me, you know, one
但对我来说
of the reasons the excite me  is
使我兴奋的原因之一
that maybe they give
就是它或许能
us this window into
给我们一些启示
what we might do if
让我们知道
we're also thinking of
当我们在思考
what algorithms might someday be
未来有什么样的算法
able to learn in a manner similar to humankind.
能以与人类相似的方式学习时 我们能做些什么